Ok,
getting a flat tire is a real pain but if you can
change it yourself it can save a lot more
delay and frustration. Once you've got the
cast slightly aside of the road,
you'll need to find the spare wheel and
tools replace to replace the flat.
In most cars the spare wheel and
replacement tools are located together
under the floor in the back. The
replacement tools consist of the jack
to raise the car so you can remove and
replace the wheel
and a range to take off the wheel nuts
that attach the wheel to the car.
Before you start to change the wheel, always
make sure the handbrake is on
and the car rise on a firm flat surface
so it can't move.
To begin with find the jacking point
closest to the wheel
that you need to replace.
If you can't find it easily, check the owner's
Manual which usually located
in the glove compartment. If the car has
a hubcap use the tool provided to remove
it.
Loosen up the wheel nut just a little
before you start jacking the car.
The wheel nut should be quite tight so you'll need
to use some strength to remove them.
If you can't do it by hand try using your
foot.
The next step is to jack up the car until the flat tire
easily clears the road.
And take the loosen wheel nut right off,
remove the wheel,
and replace it with the spare.
This might be a bit tricky but once we have
aligned up the holes in the wheel
with the corresponding screw holes on
the car, fixing the wheel nuts back
on should be relatively easy.
Tighten the wheel nuts opposite to each
other until they are firm.
Then lower the car until the wheel makes
contact with the ground.
Then tighten them firmly.
When you've done that lower the car
completely. Remove the jack
and remember to put all the tools back
where they came from.
Put the wheel with the flat tire somewhere
handy so you can take it out to the
garage door repair.